

SOPHIE WRIGHT

PILOT • CHICAGO, IL 60613, UNITED STATES . (773) 489-3264

· DETAILS ·

779 West Turtlebay Way Chicago, IL 60613 United States (773) 489-3264 swright@gmail.com

· SKILLS ·

Aircraft Technology

Spatial Awareness

Strong Communication Skills

Leadership Skills

Dedicated and experienced Pilot bringing forth the ability to fly air-crafts and perform all technical duties associated with flying at an expert level. Adept at monitoring the performance of safety systems and communicating with air traffic controllers. Able to effectively manage flight deck crews and multi-task to achieve flight success. Wholly committed to the safety and satisfaction of passengers.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Airline Pilot at United Airlines, Chicago

July 2018 - Present

- Safely and effectively operate airliners for the completion of successful flights.
- Fly passengers more than 800,000 miles without any negative incidents.
- · Continually utilize GPS and aeronautical charts without error.
- · Perform pre-flight checklists on all systems to ensure FAA safety standards.

Airline Pilot at Delta Air Lines, Atlanta

January 2014 - June 2018

- Worked tirelessly with flight crew to manage the safe and systematic operation of air-crafts.
- Calmly worked through any in-flight emergencies to support the safety and satisfaction of passengers.
- · Assigned crew members with tasks appropriately.
- · Communicated with dispatch to determine best flight routes.
- · Remained committed and focused on safe and efficient flight operations.

EDUCATION

Professional Pilot Program, Aviator College of Aeronautical Science and Technology, Fort Pierce

September 2007 - May 2009

Bachelor of Aeronautical Science, Ohio State University, Columbus

September 2003 - May 2007

REFERENCES

Robert Foster from United Airlines

rfoster@unitedpilots.org 312-485-4483

Mary Hopkins from United Airlines

mhopkins@unitedair.org 855-493-2212

Dennis Frye from Delta Air Lines

frye.dennis@deltafly.com 678-773-2188